Spencer Creer

4242 W. Old Orchard Ln. Cedar Hills, UT 84062 (385) 292-6306

spencercreer@gmail.com https://github.com/spencercreer https://spencercreer.github.io/portfolio/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/spencer-creer-023246109/

Overview

Full-stack web developer and mechanical engineer with a passion for creating applications that display data in a useful, efficient, and elegant way. Skilled in mobile-first, responsive web design using CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Tailwindcss, and React. Experienced with server and database setup with Node.js, Express, MySQL, and MongoDB. Top performing sales manager with excellent communication and team working skills.

Technical Skills

Client-side Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6+ Frameworks: Bootstrap, Tailwindcss, jQuery, React.js Server-side Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, Python

Database Structure: SQL, MySQL, Sequelize, NoSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose

Deploy Technologies: Heroku, GitHub, GitHub pages

Full-Stack Development Projects

Budget Butler

https://github.com/Jason-Jorgensen/Budget-App

- Description: A financial application for teaching saving, budgeting, and investing principles
- Role: React developer
- Technologies: MongoDB, Mongoose, Express.js, React, Node.js, Auth0, TailwindCSS

Commit Nutrition

https://github.com/spencercreer/nutrition_planner

- Description: A nutrition planning application for building meal plans and tracking nutrients
- Role: Sole developer
- Technologies: SQL, MySQL, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express.js, Heroku

8K Solar

https://github.com/spencercreer/eight-k-solar

- Description: A React web application commissioned by solar company, 8K Solar LLC.
- Role: Sole developer
- Technologies: React, JavaScript, GitHub pages, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap

Professional Experience

Moxtek, Inc., Orem, UT

Iulv 2019 to current

Sales Engineer II

- Manage the European sales of tube and detector products for the x-ray spectrometry division
- Maintain company website and improve its search engine optimization (SEO) using WordPress
- Manage customer returns and track return material authorizations (RMAs) through JIRA
- Quote new sales opportunities and inquiries
- Wrote an Excel VBA Macro to efficiently track consignment inventory cutting time by two-thirds

Advanced Composites, Inc., West Valley, UT

January 2019 to July 2019

Technical Sales Specialist

- Managed sales of composite products in the aerospace, defense, and medical industries
- Generated new business opportunities through customer relations, trade shows, and other sales activities
- Developed a more efficient shipping and packaging solution cutting costs by about \$100,000 yearly
- Worked with engineers to develop a solution to achieve more accurate and precise tolerances

New Star Communications Int. Inc., American Fork, UT

May 2014 to January 2019

Sales Manager

- Managed the Cleveland, Ohio office of twenty-seven sales representatives responsible for 1,535 new account activations equaling 1.2 million dollars of revenue growth in 2017
- Responsible for 1,152 personal accounts over four years
- Top first-year sales representative with a total of 232 personal accounts in 2014
- Amongst the top five sales representatives in production and quality four years consecutively

Education

University of Utah

November 2020 to May 2021

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate

Brigham Young University

January 2012 to December 2018

Mechanical Engineering Bachelors of Science Global Business and Literacy Minor & German Minor